Good morning, everyone, and thank you for your time.
Over the next ten minutes, I'll introduce our product — AgenticMMM — and give you a live,
end-to-end demonstration of how it delivers a real Marketing Mix Modeling project.
Before I begin, let me take one minute to frame the problem we set out to solve.
Marketing Mix Modeling — MMM for short — is a well-established discipline in marketing science.
It answers the question every marketing leader cares about most: for every dollar I spend,
how much business does it actually generate?
TV, e-commerce, offline, promotions — what is each channel's true contribution to sales?
What is the return on investment?
If I increase or cut a budget, how will sales respond?
And how should I reallocate next quarter's budget across channels to maximize return?
MMM answers these questions quantitatively, through statistical modeling on historical sales and media data.
Its value is beyond dispute — but the way it has traditionally been delivered carries a fundamental pain point.
And that is exactly what I want to talk about today.
A traditional MMM project typically takes six to twelve weeks and relies on a dedicated team of consultants, data engineers,
and modeling scientists.
But the core burden of this delivery model is not the time it takes —
it is that it places an extraordinary cognitive load on people.
In a traditional, process-driven delivery, every step depends heavily on expert judgment: how to structure the factors,
which data is usable, how to set the model priors, whether the results align with business logic.
And on top of making these judgments, the experts must also carry out an enormous amount of mechanical, repetitive,
low-value execution — cleaning data, aligning formats, tuning parameters over and over.
The high-order cognition of experts gets buried under low-order labor.
The design philosophy of AgenticMMM is built entirely around relieving that cognitive load.
We distill it into three principles.
Principle one: draw a clear line between three roles — AI, Human, and Machine —
and assign every piece of work to whichever is best suited to it.
We classify every task in the project into three kinds:
- Machine handles deterministic computation — data extraction and transformation, regression fitting, quality scoring.
This work has exactly one correct answer, so we hand it to code: fast and error-free.
- AI handles grounded generation — business interpretation, key business questions, decision recommendations.
This work requires understanding and expression, but it must be built strictly on real data and real model results.
- Human handles judgment and decisions — the critical junctures that require business experience, trade-offs, and accountability.
This division of labor frees the expert entirely from mechanical labor and concentrates their cognitive resources where a human is truly needed.
Principle two: Human-in-the-Loop, or HITL — ensuring people step in only when it is necessary.
This is critical.
We do not chase full automation, nor do we exhaust people by making them confirm everything.
The system places decision nodes at every critical quality gate —
the workflow deliberately blocks there and waits for human confirmation, while everywhere else,
AI and Machine advance autonomously, without interruption.
Here is an example: data validation uses a three-state score.
A pass is cleared automatically; an unusable metric is discarded automatically with an alert; and only the borderline,
questionable metrics bring a person into the decision.
A person's attention is therefore directed precisely to where judgment is most needed, rather than consumed indiscriminately.
Principle three works on two levels — Artifacts-Driven and Human-Intuitive.
Being Artifacts-Driven means the entire workflow is organized around concrete deliverables, rather than an opaque,
black-box process.
This yields four practical benefits.
First, visible progress — the status of every deliverable is clear at a glance.
Second, controllable quality — every deliverable is a natural unit for human review and sign-off.
Third, full traceability — every deliverable carries version history and lineage,
so the final report can be traced all the way back to the model, data, and interviews it rests on.
Fourth, reliable propagation — the moment a deliverable is rejected,
every affected downstream output is automatically reset and rebuilt, so no inconsistency is ever left behind.
Being Human-Intuitive means the system presents work the way a person thinks,
rather than forcing the person to adapt to the machine's logic.
A project unfolds naturally along the hierarchy of Stage → Deliverable → build process;
business factors are presented as an intuitive factor tree; items requiring a decision are gathered into a single, clear inbox.
The user needs to learn no complex system concepts — everything is presented in the business language they already know.
Built on this philosophy, the core of the product is carried by three interfaces.
Let me walk through each.
First, Workflow.
This is the methodology blueprint the product crystallizes, visualized as a directed acyclic graph, a DAG.
The horizontal axis is the five delivery stages; the vertical swim lanes are the five agents.
Every task node is labeled with its collaboration mode — whether it is executed autonomously by Machine, generated by AI,
or requires human intervention.
Click any node to see its inputs, outputs, dependencies, and reasoning log.
This single diagram is the complete picture of how the project runs.
Second, Project.
This is the primary workspace for execution and delivery, and the direct embodiment of the Artifacts-Driven principle.
The interface is organized along the hierarchy of Stage spine → Deliverable list → build process: the stage progress sits at the top,
the full set of deliverables for that stage on the left, and the main area shows exactly how each deliverable is built.
The real materials a project needs are uploaded through the Project Folder;
items requiring human confirmation are handled right here.
All of the user's day-to-day work happens in this one interface.
Third, Knowledge.
This is the platform's hub for accumulation and reuse.
MMM industry knowledge — factor templates, interview frameworks, validation rules — is accumulated here, organized by industry,
editable, maintainable, and versioned.
Every new project inherits the relevant industry's knowledge base from here;
and every confirmation and correction a person makes during a project flows back and enriches this knowledge base.
The platform therefore grows smarter with every project it runs.
Enough talk — let the results speak for themselves.
What I have open here is a project that has already run to completion — Danone China's Mizone,
23,800 rows of genuine modeling data across three major channels: AFH, TT, and MT.
Traditionally, this is six to twelve weeks of output from a full expert team.
Over the next few minutes, I'll walk you through its results from the top,
and I'd ask you to watch just one thing: behind these results, how did the three roles — AI, Human, and Machine —
divide the work and collaborate to produce them.
Stage one, Business Understanding.
This used to be the most cognitively demanding part of the entire project — a consultant poring over the Statement of Work,
industry reports, and a dozen interview transcripts, then hand-drawing a factor tree from experience.
First, this project scope — framed automatically by the Business Agent after it read the client's SOW: product lines, channels,
regions, and time granularity, all of it, and all held strictly within the bounds that make modeling feasible — one product line,
no more than four channels (one online, plus MT, TT, and AFH offline), no more than six geography or platform groups.
These constraints aren't arbitrary; they're industry rules built into the product.
Now this factor tree — the master data spine of the whole project.
The top layers, L1 and L2, are the industry-universal structure, recalled at 100%; below them,
L3 and L4 were generated by the agent from knowledge of Mizone's category,
with 10 to 20 percent open to additions or deletions on the default list.
These added nodes you see all carry their source, plainly labeled — some from AI recommendation,
some from the brand's financial reports, some from interviews; and for every addition or deletion, the system recorded the reason,
to feed back into the knowledge base.
And the crux is in these flagged nodes.
AI ran through the entire process, yet it never decided for anyone.
Every factor the AI added was, at the time, placed in front of a person to confirm or reject;
and every one of those judgments flowed back into the knowledge base, making the platform smarter with use.
This is what AI-Native collaboration looks like: AI and Machine carry all the heavy lifting,
and the human appears only where a real decision must be made.
The interview step shows this even more fully.
This interview outline is layered — different questions for interviewees at different levels;
and the agent generated only the questions that truly needed validating in person,
after it had first read all existing materials and drafted its own first-pass answers.
Once the interview notes came back, it compared them automatically and highlighted, right on the factor tree,
what should change and why — the person only had to confirm.
Following on, this is the structured data-request document it generated — each L3 factor as one table, L4 as sub-tables,
the columns being the metric granularity and the metrics themselves, so the client can gather exactly the right data.
And finally, the scope, factor tree, and interview insights were all folded into a single Business Understanding summary.
A stage that once took weeks — its results, all here in front of you.
Stage two, Data Intake & Quality.
Once the data was back, this used to be a data engineer's most grueling weeks.
The Data Agent lives by one creed — 'rubbish in, rubbish out'; data quality is model quality —
so it guards this stage most strictly.
Look at this data-quality scorecard: it's scored row by row, from L1, L2, L3, L4, all the way down to each individual metric.
And the score isn't a single check — it's four dimensions at once: consistency — are the caliber, time, and dimensions unified;
accuracy — do the values and business caliber reconcile with finance; comprehensiveness —
any missing fields or gaps at the modeling granularity; and granularity — is time fine enough,
can it break down to the drill dimensions.
Each item lands in one of three tiers: a full score is cleared automatically, a zero is discarded with an alert —
and if a factor's only metrics all score zero, the alert is escalated.
This 0.5 metric here is the one that was flagged as borderline and questionable,
and brought specifically to a person to decide how to handle.
Hundreds, thousands of mechanical checks — the Machine absorbed on its own;
the human's attention landed precisely on the one place that needed judgment.
Once validation passes comes the integration pipeline.
This Danone case was broken into more than thirty data-processing tasks, and the processing logic for each — how channels map,
how product lines match, how negatives are handled — was proposed by AI, iterated over several rounds,
and then confirmed by two people cross-checking each other.
It all integrates into this unified wide-table master dataset on the right.
Notice one elegant thing: the columns of this wide table are exactly the factor tree's L1 through L8 —
the business structure and the data structure are one and the same.
Together with this data dictionary, every step from raw data to final dataset is traceable.
Stage three, Validation & Hypotheses.
Clean isn't enough — the data has to withstand two interrogations at once, business and statistical,
and out of it we have to distill the priors for modeling.
First, business validation.
The Data Agent drills down through the factor tree layer by layer,
using a six-step method to check whether each metric makes commercial sense;
then it auto-generates charts and trend interpretations for the client to sign off on — another gate guarded by a human.
Once cleared comes statistical validation: coefficient of variation to see if the volatility is abnormal,
correlation to see its relationship with sales, collinearity — VIF — to see whether variables interfere with one another,
scoring and screening each.
Then it runs a quick OLS pre-fit as a check, producing rough contribution and ROI ranges for each factor,
confirming the business-level read agrees with the data, and finally locking the model-input list you see here now.
More importantly, this stage also distilled the modeling priors — the likely elasticity range of a given channel,
that a competitor's effect should be negative, that brand search leads sales by one to two weeks.
Each of these hypotheses carries its source and was confirmed by the client, becoming a constraint for the next stage's modeling.
Business intuition and statistical rigor, brought together in one system for the first time.
Stage four, Modeling.
The first step is model choice: when you need to iterate ROI quickly, use OLS linear fitting;
when you need high precision at every level and want to feed business priors in to guide the result,
use a Bayesian probabilistic model.
The formal modeling for this case used a hierarchical model that can absorb priors.
Those business hypotheses from the last stage were translated here into mathematical constraints — the bounds on elasticity,
the shape of diminishing returns, a competitor coefficient truncated to negative, the lag order.
Every prior traces all the way back to the business hypothesis and the client confirmation behind it.
Here I'll draw a hard line: every number you see in the report — adstock, saturation curves, each channel's contribution and ROI —
comes from a real regression engine, computed one by one, not conjured up by a language model.
AI-Native never means letting AI make things up; what should be computed is left, faithfully, to computation.
After tuning comes technical validation — and not on a single metric, but multi-dimensional cross-validation: R² for overall fit,
MAPE for prediction accuracy, Durbin-Watson for residual autocorrelation,
plus residual normality and whether the contribution decomposition is reasonable.
There are also two hard red flags — the moment a 'negative Base' or a 'negative coefficient' appears,
the model must be fixed before it can be used.
Only when all of that passes does model selection come.
These here are the Pareto-optimal candidates the system produced, laid out side by side.
The system never picks for anyone automatically — the one finally chosen was this one, owned by a person.
Because choosing a model is, at its core, a business trade-off.
This is a principle we've hard-wired into the product.
Stage five, Reporting.
The Report Agent turned cold coefficients into an entire language the business understands.
Behind it sits a standard metric system — volume contribution, value contribution, ROI, spend share, contribution share,
unit cost, effectiveness — ten concepts, one consistent caliber.
Look at this report: this is the decomposition chart,
showing you exactly how sales break down into Base plus the contribution of each channel; this is the Due-to chart,
attributing 'why did sales rise or fall this period' to each individual channel; this is the ROI chart,
where every channel's return sits next to an industry benchmark line —
with a deliberate caution that upper-funnel channels have naturally lower ROI yet real value, and can't be extrapolated linearly.
Going further, it can even explain 'why did ROI change' —
through a four-quadrant view of effectiveness and cost: effectiveness up and cost down, invest more;
effectiveness down and cost up, refresh the creative or renegotiate the price.
Every chart is three layers stacked — a templated chart, an interpretation template, and AI adding business-contextual narration —
so it's both standard and business-savvy.
And you can question it directly, say, 'Why does this channel have the highest ROI?' — it answers,
grounded in the real model results.
But here is the real highlight: the model is not the finish line — it's the starting line.
This simulator, delivered to the client, can be re-run at any time — set the total budget and your hard business constraints,
and it runs a marginal optimization on the real response curves,
telling you directly how to split the money for the greatest return.
Traditionally, a modeling team would compute this one question for days; here, it's seconds,
and you can play out as many scenarios as you like.
A real MMM project, carried all the way from a single SOW to an executable budget recommendation —
that is what it ultimately delivers.
In a little over ten minutes, we have walked through a complete, real MMM project.
Let me close on three points.
First, this is AI-Native, not AI-attached.
We did not bolt a chat box onto legacy software; we rebuilt from the skeleton of the process outward.
The methodology is crystallized into a visible workflow, AI, Human, and Machine each play their proper role,
and AI reaches into every step rather than floating on the surface.
Second, it relieves the cognitive burden on people — it does not replace their judgment.
Machine takes on mechanical computation, AI takes on grounded generation, and the human — through Human-in-the-Loop —
is called precisely to every juncture that genuinely requires judgment: not one interruption too many, not one checkpoint too few.
Everything is artifacts-driven, visible, and traceable, presented in a way people already understand.
Third, it delivers not just a report, but a lasting decision capability.
Once the model is complete, you can return to the simulator at any time to play out any budget scenario;
and the platform keeps evolving as each project deposits knowledge into it.
For a brand, this means three things: a faster delivery cycle, a lower project cost, and — because the entire process is visible,
controllable, and traceable — results you can trust more.
Thank you.
I'd be glad to run through any specific scenario you care about, live, right now.